

SUMMARY

QA engineer with 3+ years of experience in software testing: web and mobile applications. I took part in quality assurance of two projects related to e-commerce. Have proficiency in conducting such types of testing as functional, GUI, UAT and integration.

Also, I have been working as Lead QA Engineer on the second project and managed 10+ manual and auto QA Engineers. On a regular basis helped to improve testing processes: created an onboarding program for newcomers, proposed new methods of task estimation and holding retrospectives.

SKILLS

Git

Agile methodologies

CI/CD

Team management

Test design

Task estimation

Functional testing

UI/UX testing

API testing

SQL

DevTools

Graylog

Kibana

Jenkins

Fiddler

Jira

English level - Intermediate

OLGA

Dubovik

QA Engineer

Location: Minsk, Belarus LINKEDIN: o dubovik

Email: olgaa.dubovik@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

QA Test Lead

Traektoria kachestva. Minsk

July 2022-present

Project - one of the largest marketplace in Russia.

Responsibilities as Lead QA:

- Managing a team of 10+ engineers;
- Setting up and updating project processes;
- Creating test plans and tasks prioritization;
- Leading daily meetings, retros, demos;
- Planning test activities;
- Release management;
- Preparing reports on test results;
- Tracking and providing visibility on test progress;
- Onboarding newcomers, communication with the customer;
- Issues solving;
- Team motivation.

Responsibilities as QA Engineer:

- Functional testing of web and mobile apps (iOS, Android);
- API testing;
- A/B testing;
- Designing, developing, executing and maintaining test cases and other test documentation;
- Creating feature files for automation testing;
- Release holding: creating release branch (GIT), launching auto tests, deploying branch to test and prod environment;
- Defect tracking and verification;
- Performing smoke and regression testing;
- Active communication with team members: PO, BA, SA, Devs, Designers;
- Taking part in all scrum processes.

QA Engineer

A1QA, Minsk

December 2020 - July 2022

Project - Marketing and e-commerce solution for multinational manufacturer and marketer of home appliances

• Functional testing of web application;

- Designing, developing, executing and maintaining test cases and other test documentation;
- Defect tracking and verification;
- Performing smoke and regression testing;
- Communication with team members;
- Working in multitasking mode as project consist of more than 10 products with their own web applications/

Economist

Sveni-L, Minsk

February 2018 - September 2020

- Acceptance of goods;
- Pricing of goods;
- Inputting information of goods arrival to 1C ERP;
- Preparing management reports.

EDUCATION

QA Academy at A1QA

«Basic of testing software»
«Advanced course for QA with individual support»
«QA English basics»

Belarusian state economic university

September 2014 - June 2018 Bachelor